http://www.blackburn.ac.uk/privacy-and-cookies/

Find Your Course
Why Blackburn University Centre?
Which Course Should I Choose?
Professional Qualifications
Fees and Financial Support
Finance Information for 2021 Entry
Full-Time Finance Information (2021 Entry)
Part-Time Finance Information (2021 Entry)
Student Engagement Team
Information For Students With Disabilities and Emotional Health and Wellbeing Service
Additional Information
Wider Information Set (WIS)
Make An Enquiry
What Can We Offer To Your Business?
St Paul's Centre
Regional Automotive Technology Hub (RATH)
Privacy and Cookies
The General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and your personal data
In May 2018 the rules governing how we manage data changed to become more rigorous. Data protection affects every single customer of the College, including staff and students, and the following articles explains what you can expect from the College.
What is data protection?
Blackburn College collects and processes a range of data from its students, from details of your previous qualifications and attendance marks, to the grades you achieve whilst studying with us. Data protection legislation sets out the requirements for how the College, as a data controller, processes personal data. Personal data is defined as any data that identifies or is likely to identify a living individual, including facts and opinions.The College is fully committed to the principles of data protection, as set out in the Data Protection Act 2018. We process and maintain personal data about you so that we can manage your student journey, submit official data to relevant government bodies, and manage your experience at Blackburn College. In accordance with the Data Protection Act, we have a legal duty to protect any information we collect from you. So for example, we will only use your information for the purpose as described. We do not pass on your details to third parties unless you have given us permission to do so, or there is a legal obligation or statutory requirement to do so. You also have the right to ask for a copy of the information we hold about you and to have any inaccuracies in your information corrected.
What’s changing?
On 25 May 2018, the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) replaced the current Data Protection Act.The eight principles of the existing data protection act still apply but the new regulation means there will be greater transparency around areas such as consent, privacy notices, reporting of breaches and transfer of data outside the EU.We have been working over the last 8 months to ensure our already comprehensive policies meet the requirements of the new, and more rigorous legislation. This has included reviewing our processes and procedures around key areas such as security and retention of data, subject access requests and data breaches, and bringing our policies up to date.We are also undertaking an internal review of what data we collect, and who we share this with.
How will this affect existing and prospective students?
The College will continue to respect and protect the personal data we collect about you.
We will be adding to/amending our data protection disclaimers in light of the GDPR, so you might notice changes to our application and enrolment forms. It is important that you understand what we are doing with your data. We will enhance our privacy notices on the website and on any new systems you register for, to inform you, at the point that we collect your data, about why we are collecting it, how we will use it and how we keep it safe.The majority of personal data we collect about you is necessary and for the legitimate purposes of the organisation e.g. individual data to be submitted to official government bodies.
Requesting the data we hold about you
If you would like to request a copy of the personal data we hold about you, please refer to our data protection policy.
Criminal Convictions
As an applicant to Blackburn College you will be asked to declare any unspent criminal convictions and/or inform the College of any convictions that are obtained whilst a student.
Blackburn College serves the community inclusive of children and thus all individuals will be asked about any unspent criminal history in order for a safeguarding assessment to be exercised.
In rare instances individuals may be denied access to the institution due to the nature of unspent convictions or appropriate control measures will be suggested.
Further information
If you’d like to find out more about the GDPR changes, please see the Information Commissioner’s Office website. If you have any specific questions about the data protection policy and how GDPR affects you, please contact us via the following email address dataprotection@blackburn.ac.uk You can also read our data protection policy
Right to be forgotten
If you no longer wish Blackburn College to store or use your personal data, please refer to our data protection policy.
Aisha Ali - Business with Law Level 3 Extended Dip...
"I have enjoyed absolutely everything about the Bu...
Extraordinary Journey for Former Blackburn College...
Former Blackburn College Level 3 Business with Law...
Blackburn College Barbers Welcome Clients for Safe...
Level 3 and Level 2 Blackburn College Barbering st...
Myles Campbell - Level 3 Extended Diploma in Sport...
"My favourite area of the course is the Leadership...
Hannah Fish - Beauty Therapy Level 3
"My tutor Sally has been amazing with her support ...
Ellie Clayton - Level 2 Beauty Therapy
"I am a hardworking and enthusiastic person who is...
Blackburn College Launches New Advance Employabili...
Blackburn College has launched its new Advance Emp...
Amy and Lawrence Named Winners of Blackburn Colleg...
Amy Forrest and Lawrence Silcock have been named a...
